[
    {
        "question": "मनगढंत",
        "options": [
            "अपादान तत्पुरुष",
            "करण तत्पुरुष",
            "कर्म तत्पुरुष",
            "संबंध तत्पुरुष"
        ],
        "answer": "करण तत्पुरुष"
    },
    {
        "question": " निधड़क",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " थोड़ा - बहुत",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास"
        ],
        "answer": "द्वंद्व समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " अनाचार",
        "options": [
            "नञ् तत्पुरुष",
            "कर्म तत्पुरुष",
            "संबंध तत्पुरुष",
            "अपादान तत्पुरुष"
        ],
        "answer": "नञ् तत्पुरुष"
    },
    {
        "question": " सज्जन",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " बखूबी",
        "options": [
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " मदोन्मत",
        "options": [
            "अपादान तत्पुरुष",
            "संबंध तत्पुरुष",
            "कर्म तत्पुरुष",
            "करण तत्पुरुष"
        ],
        "answer": "करण तत्पुरुष"
    },
    {
        "question": " पंचतत्व",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "द्विगु समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " कुरूप",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " भरसक",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " महाराजा",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " न्यूनाधिक",
        "options": [
            "द्विगु समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास"
        ],
        "answer": "द्वंद्व समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " विषधर",
        "options": [
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "बहुब्रीहि समास"
        ],
        "answer": "बहुब्रीहि समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " महारथी",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " यथा संभव",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " पंचानन",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "बहुब्रीहि समास"
        ],
        "answer": "बहुब्रीहि समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " त्रिकुटी",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "द्विगु समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " हाथों हाथ",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " वाचस्पति",
        "options": [
            "अलुक तत्पुरुष",
            "कर्म तत्पुरुष",
            "अपादान तत्पुरुष",
            "करण तत्पुरुष"
        ],
        "answer": "अलुक तत्पुरुष"
    },
    {
        "question": " कर - पल्लव",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " नवरत्न",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास"
        ],
        "answer": "द्विगु समास"
    },
    {
        "question": "पंचतंत्र",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "द्विगु समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " गुरु भाई",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "तत्पुरुष समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "बहुब्रीहि समास"
        ],
        "answer": "तत्पुरुष समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " कर्म - कुशल",
        "options": [
            "अधिकरण तत्पुरुष",
            "कर्म तत्पुरुष",
            "अपादान तत्पुरुष",
            "संबंध तत्पुरुष"
        ],
        "answer": "अधिकरण तत्पुरुष"
    },
    {
        "question": " गिरिधर",
        "options": [
            "बहुब्रीहि समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास"
        ],
        "answer": "बहुब्रीहि समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " सुयोग",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " भरसक",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " आजानुबाहु",
        "options": [
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "बहुब्रीहि समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास"
        ],
        "answer": "बहुब्रीहि समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " कनकलता",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " प्रतिदिन",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " जन्मांध",
        "options": [
            "संबंध तत्पुरुष",
            "कर्म तत्पुरुष",
            "करण तत्पुरुष",
            "अपादान तत्पुरुष"
        ],
        "answer": "अपादान तत्पुरुष"
    },
    {
        "question": " आमरण",
        "options": [
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास",
            "द्विगु समास"
        ],
        "answer": "अव्ययीभाव समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " दही - बड़ा",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास"
        ],
        "answer": "कर्मधारय समास"
    },
    {
        "question": " कामचोर",
        "options": [
            "संबंध तत्पुरुष",
            "कर्म तत्पुरुष",
            "अपादान तत्पुरुष",
            "करण तत्पुरुष"
        ],
        "answer": "अपादान तत्पुरुष"
    },
    {
        "question": " अष्टाध्यायी",
        "options": [
            "कर्मधारय समास-",
            "द्वंद्व समास",
            "द्विगु समास",
            "अव्ययीभाव समास"
        ],
        "answer": "द्विगु समास"
    }
]